# Eric (Binqian) Zeng

40 Memorial Hwy. Apt. 05R, New Rochelle, NY, 10801

□ +1 929-208-7103 • ☑ bz866@nyu.edu; ericzengsearch@gmail.com • https://www.linkedin.com/in/bingian-zeng-257903126/ • https://github.com/bz866

### Introduction

One-year working experience as a Data Scientist; Master's level education background in Machine Learning and Financial Mathematics. Python & C/C++ programmer. Skilled in quantitative/machine learning modeling. Familiar with database, big data analysis, and cloud computing. Experienced in collaborating with the trading desk and the research team. Seeking full-time opportunities in the cross of technology and finance.

# **Work Experience**

## Swiss Reinsurance Company Ltd. (Swiss Re)

Armonk, NY Jan 2019–Present

Analytics Specialist/Data Scientist

\* Catastrophe Loss Impact Estimation using Machine Learning Models

- Estimate the loss of catastrophes(wild fire, flood, etc.) using satellite images, coverage policies, and geographic data from various resources(Geographic Zonal Statistic, Random Forest Regression, Neural Network, Python, TensorFlow, ArcGIS)
- \* Insurance Policies Dataset Management & Cluster Configuration
  - Aggregated metadata description for big datasets(billions of records); ETL for data mining(SQL); Backtested hypothesis and correlation(SparkML); Clustering(SparkML); Configured the cloud computing clusters(Linux)
- \* Home Renters Insurance Go-to-market Analysis
  - Identified home rental insurance market opportunities in New York State using self-designed opportunity scoring metrics(Significance Test, Linear Regression); Visualized in an interactive dashboard (Python, JavaScript)

#### King Street Capital Management, L.P.

New York, NY

Jul 2018-Dec 2018

Data Science Intern (full-time)

\* Companies KPI Forecasting Model

- Forecasted KPIs of companies using an ensemble model; All base and top learners are SVMs with different constraints
- Handled collinearity in meta-features by matrix factorization; Reduced overfitting by ridge regularization and noise injection(SQL, Python, Scikit-learn)
- \* Analyzing Alpha in Corporate Filings
  - Categorized companies with high and low information ratio based on corporate fillings using RNN and attention mechanism
  - Generated sentence representation with word-embedding that is optimized by financial news
  - Involved statistical features by capturing textual changes over time(Python, NLTK, TensorFlow)

# Crypto Investments

New York, NY

Machine Learning Engineer Intern

Sep 2017-Dec 2017

- \* Event-Driven Forecasting Model for Price of Cryptocurrencies
  - Web-scrapped cryptocurrencies news and trade data by API; Data management for scrapped data(Python, MongoDB)
  - News sentiment analysis by Word2Vec; Event embedding by Open IE; Captured effects of different time spans by CNN

# **Technical Skills & Certificates**

- Programming & Scripting Language: Python, C/C++, Java, Scala, R, Matlab
- Toolkits, Softwares & Operating Systems: MySQL, Spark, Hadoop, AWS, Tensorflow, Pytorch, Keras, NLTK, Scikit-learn, Numpy, Pandas, Github, Linux/Unix

# **Education**

# New York University, Courant Institute of Mathematical Sciences

New York, NY

Mathematics in Finance; part-time graduate program on-going

Jan 2019 - Present

Courseworks: Derivative Securities, Operating System(C/C++), Risk and Portfolio Management with Econometrics, Financial Modeling

# New York University, Courant Institute of Mathematical Sciences

New York, NY

M.S Data Science; GPA: 3.3/4.0;

Sep 2016 – May 2018

Courseworks: Machine Learning, Natural Language Processing(Kyunghyun Cho), Deep Learning(Yann LeCun), Statistical and Mathematical Methods, Big Data(Hadoop MapReduce, Spark), Data Science in Quantitative Finance, Advance Python Programming

#### Sun Yat-sen University, School of Engineering

Guangzhou, China

B.E Engineering Mechanics (Fluid Dynamics Focus); GPA: 3.7/4.0

Sep 2012 - Jun 2016

Honor: Annual scholarship (three years)

Courseworks: Numerical Methods, Finite element analysis, Ordinary Differential Equations, Fluid Dynamics, Linear Algebra

#### **Portfolio**

# **Operating System Components**

**Keywords:** C/C++, Operating System, Object-oriented Programming

- Linker; Process Scheduler(discrete event simulation model); Virtual Memory Management Unit; I/O Scheduler

#### Text Summarization Neural Network for News

- Keywords: Python, Pytorch, Bidirectional-LSTM, Attention Mechanism, Pointer Network, Semantic Relevance
- A hybrid of extractive and abstractive approaches text summarization model trained on CNN/Daily Mail news
- Bi-LSTM encoder with attention mechanism; Pointer Network improves the accuracy of words generation and the ability of handling out-of-vocabulary words; Semantic relevance encouraged loss function

#### Commodity Trading Position Forecasting Model

- Keywords: Python, Alpha Strategy, Matrix Factorization, Regularization, Linear Regression
- Created a regression model that forecasts the optimal trading positions for oil, sugar, copper, gold, and natural gas futures
- Estimated covariance models; Explained the variance of asset classes by top alpha factors; Signal filtering down by SVD